

Ph.D. STUDENT IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AT GEORGIA INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY

■ seongmin@gatech.edu | # https://www.seongmin.xyz | Seongmin Lee | Seongmin Lee | @ Seongmin Lee

Summary_

I'm a Ph.D. student in Computer Science at Georgia Tech, advised by Professor Polo Chau. My research aims to provide explanations and interpretations for various machine learning techniques based on visualization. I received my B.S. in Electrical and Computer Engineering from Seoul National University in February 2021. I have collaborated with researchers and developers of Cisco Systems, Inc. and AVAST Software.

Education

Georgia Institute of Technology

Georgia, USA

Ph.D. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

Seoul National University

Aug. 2021 - Present

Advisor: Prof. Duen Horng (Polo) Chau

Seoul, South Korea

B.S. IN ELECTRICAL AND COMPUTER ENGINEERING

Mar. 2016 - Feb. 2021

Graduated with Summa Cum Laude. Overall GPA: 3.91/4.0, Major GPA: 3.94/4.0

Korea Science Academy of KAIST

Busan, South Korea

MATH AND SCIENCE SPECIALIZED HIGH SCHOOL

Feb. 2013 - Feb. 2016

One year early entrance, Graduated with distinction in GPA

Research Experience

Cisco Systems, Inc.

California, USA (Remote)

 PhD Intern
 May. 2022 - Jul. 2022

Mentor: Ali Payani

- · Added machine learning explanation and visualization features to RAI, a (to be) open-sourced project for responsible AI.
- · Improved disentangled representation learning algorithms and visualized the results for better interpretability.
- Investigated CNNs by visualizing how the concepts in the input images affect the feature representations from the neural networks using synthetic data.

Polo Club of Data Science, Georgia Institute of Technology

Georgia, USA

GRADUATE RESEARCH ASSISTANT

Aug. 2021 - Present

Advisor: Duen Horng (Polo) Chau

- Led a project to help people assess website reliability by providing visual explanations of how each website engages in spreading false information
- Developed an interactive visualization tool to detect biases in CNN classifiers.
- Participating in a project to investigate how a concept evolves while training neural networks.

Data Mining Lab, Seoul National University

Undergraduate Research Internship and Bachelor's Thesis

Seoul, South Korea

Jan. 2020 - Feb. 2021

Advisor: Prof. U Kang

Undergraduate Research Internship

- Investigated multi-source domain adaptation under various constraints and settings.
- Resolved the limitation of BERT that the tasks with few training data are hard to fine-tune by pruning proper attention heads based on reinforcement learning.

Communication and Machine Learning Laboratory, Seoul National University

Seoul, South Korea

Sep. 2019 - Apr. 2020

Advisor: Prof. Jungwoo Lee

• Studied the problem of class imbalance and uncertainty in semantic segmentation.

Biomedical Precision Laboratory, The University of Tokyo

Tokyo, Japan

Undergraduate Research Internship

Jul. 2018 - Aug. 2018

Advisor: Dr. Keiichi Nakagawa, Dr. Ayumu Ishijima

- Collaborated with 3 students majoring in biology and physics to observe interaction between human cells and acoustic waves.
- · Constructed a microscopic motion-picture camera with sub-nano spatial/temporal resolution using optical equipments and laser.
- Processed the microscopic images using Matlab for better analysis.

June 21, 2023 Seongmin Lee · Résumé

Publications, Preprints, Demos

Diffusion Explainer: Visual Explanation for Text-to-image Stable Diffusion

Seongmin Lee, Benjamin Hoover, Hendrik Strobelt, Zijie J. Wang, ShengYun Peng, Austin Wright, Kevin Li, Haekyu Park, Haoyang Yang, Duen Horng Chau

arXiv Preprints (arXiv), 2023

SuperNOVA: Design Strategies and Opportunities for Interactive Visualization in Computational Notebooks

Zijie J. Wang, David Munechika, **Seongmin Lee**, Duen Horng Chau arXiv Preprints (arXiv), 2023

Diffusion Explainer: Interactive Visual Learning for Stable Diffusion

Seongmin Lee, Benjamin Hoover, Hendrik Strobelt, Zijie J. Wang, ShengYun Peng, Austin Wright, Kevin Li, Haekyu Park, Haoyang Yang, Duen Horng (Polo) Chau

Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR) Demo Track, 2023

Explaining Website Reliability by Visualizing Hyperlink Connectivity

Seongmin Lee, Sadia Afroz, Haekyu Park, Zijie J. Wang, Omar Shaikh, Vibhor Sehgal, Ankit Peshin, Duen Horng (Polo) Chau IEEE Visualization and Visual Analytics (VIS), 2022

ConceptEvo: Interpreting Concept Evolution in Deep Learning Training

Haekyu Park, **Seongmin Lee**, Benjamin Hoover, Austin Wright, Omar Shaikh, Rahul Duggal, Nilaksh Das, Judy Hoffman, Duen Horng (Polo) Chau

arXiv Preprints (arXiv), 2022

NOVA: A Practical Method for Creating Notebook-Ready Visual Analytics

Zijie J. Wang, David Munechika, **Seongmin Lee**, Duen Horng (Polo) Chau IEEE Visualization and Visual Analytics (VIS) Poster, 2022

VisCUIT: Visual Auditor for Bias in CNN Image Classifier

Seongmin Lee, Zijie J. Wang, Judy Hoffman, Duen Horng Chau

Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR) Demo Track, 2022

MisVis: Explaining Web Misinformation Connections via Visual Summary

Seongmin Lee, Sadia Afroz, Haekyu Park, Zijie J. Wang, Omar Shaikh, Vibhor Sehgal, Ankit Peshin, Duen Horng (Polo) Chau CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems Extended Abstracts, 2022

Multi-EPL: Accurate Multi-Source Domain Adaptation

Seongmin Lee, Hyunsik Jeon, U Kang

PLOS ONE, 2021

AUBER: Automated BERT Regularization

Hyun Dong Lee * , **Seongmin Lee^***, U Kang (* These authors contributed equally to this work) PLOS ONE, 2021

Unsupervised Multi-Source Domain Adaptation with No Observable Source Data

Hyunsik Jeon, **Seongmin Lee**, U Kang

PLOS ONE, 2021

Patent.

Pruning Method for Attention Head in Transformer Neural Networks for Regularization and Apparatus Thereof

Seongmin Lee, Hyun Dong Lee, and U Kang

10-2020-0162397, 2020

Honors & Awards

The Presidential Science Scholarship

KOREA SCIENCE AID FOUNDATION

SNU Engineering Honor Society (STEM)

COLLEGE OF ENGINEERING, SNU

Voluntary Service Award

DEPARTMENT OF ELECTRICAL AND COMPUTER ENGINEERING, SNU

Mar. 2016 - Dec. 2019

Mar. 2018 - Dec. 2019

Dec. 2018, Dec. 2017

June 21, 2023 Seongmin Lee · Résumé 2

Talks

"STEM Global Engineer Seminar", Seoul National University, SNU Engineering Honor Society (STEM)	May. 2023
"MisVis: Explaining Web Misinformation Connections via Visual Summary", Georgia Tech, School of CSE Recruiting Event	Nov. 2022
"Explaining Website Reliability by Visualizing Hyperlink Connectivity", AVAST Software, Fake News Monthly Sync Up	Spring 2022
"Multi-Source Domain Adaptation with Pseudo-labels", Seoul National University, AllS Retreat	Jun. 2020

Teaching

Data and Visual Analytics (CSE 6242), Graduate Teaching Assistant	Fall 2022
Deep Learning Course for LG Chem, Lab session lecturer	Jan. 2021
Deep Learning Course for SK Hynix, Lab session lecturer	Nov. 2020
Introduction to Algorithm, SNU, Undergraduate student tutor	Fall 2020, Fall 2019
Introduction to Physics I, SNU, Undergraduate student tutor	Spring 2017

Grants and Funding

Meta Research Funding (\$50k)

PIs: Polo Chau

Co-authored proposal on developing novel visualization to curb and quantify misinformation consumption.

Cisco Research Funding (\$150k)

Pls: Polo Chau

Co-authored proposal.

Skills____

Programming C/C++, Python, Java, Verilog, HTML/CSS/Javascript

Frameworks Tensorflow, PyTorch

Languages Korean (Native), English (iBT: 109 (R28/L28/S26/W27), GRE: Verbal 163, Writing 4.5)

Extracurricular Activity _____

GTKSA (Georgia Tech Korean Student Association) Aug. 2021 - Present

Serving as a secretary and web administrator.

SNU Buddy Sep. 2020 - Dec. 2020

Buddy program for the international exchange students. Used to be a group leader.

SNU Engineering Honor Society (STEM) Mar. 2018 - Dec. 2019

Organized academic seminars, international round table, and mentoring programs as a vice president.

Vision Mentoring, Seoul National University Jul. 2019

Lectured high school students on engineering (More than 700 students attended)

Dream Camp Mentoring, Seoul National University Feb. 2019, Feb. 2018

Educated high school students in the countryside by designing a mentoring program

Student Vice President Nov. 2017 - Oct. 2018

Elected as a vice president of the Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering, SNU

Student Reporter Sep. 2017 - Feb. 2021

Published brochures about the Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering every semester

Talent Sharing Volunteer Camp, KOSAF Jan. 2017, Aug. 2016

Conducted self-planned mentoring for elementary school students in underprivileged areas in Korea